HAFILA NAZRIN

Data Analyst

Tel: +91 6379232500 | Email: hafilanaz6@gmail.com
Tamil Nadu, India – 623406
LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

As an aspiring data analyst with a career gap of two years. Fighting All the way to get into the world of data with an immense amount of interest in Mathematics and handling data. Self-taught student with the help of online resources.

PROJECTS:

POWERBI

Hospitality Revenue Analysis

Created a report in the Hospitality Domain using the Key Metrics such as Revenue, RevPar, ADR, Occupany. A Table representing the key metrics of the Property including Realisation, Cancellation, Average rating and Charts regarding the Online Platform.

Bike Share Analysis

Developed a dashboard that displays key metrics for informed decision-making regarding Hourly Revenue Analysis, Seasonal Revenue, Rider Demographics and provided with better insights.

SOL

HR Report regarding Absenteeism

Dashboard for HR to understand Absenteeism at work based on approved wireframe. Also Calculated wage increase for Healthy Employee.

EXCEL

Coffee sales dashboard

I took on a project to analyse sales data from a coffee shop. After analysing the data I created an interactive dashboard that serves as a valuable tool for coffee shop owner and presented them visually using Excel.

TABLEAU

Overall Reviews of British Airways

Took the overall review of the Airways and prepared a report based on the reviews from the Passengers and displayed it in the Dashboard which helps in making strategic decisions for the area where it needs to be focused for better improvement.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NOVITECH R&D Pvt Ltd, Tamil Nadu (Data Analyst Intern)

July 2024 - Present

Performed exploratory data analysis on large customer dataset using SQL and Python. Designed dashboards and visualizations regarding Customer need. Identified factors influencing purchasing decisions and made data-driven recommendations

SPACE ZEE TECHNOLOGIES, Chennai, Tamil Nadu (Embedded Engineer Intern)

May 2022 - June 2022

Learned new technologies of embedded systems, handled hardware and software. Used Relay, Ultrasonic sensor to build Automation. Designed Air Pollution Monitor and Light Automation using C programming

EDUCATION

MOHAMED SATHAK ENGINEERING COLLEGE, KILAKARAI B.E – ECE (CGPA-8.72)

2018-2022

Focus: Learned about IOT and Home Automation

MUSLIM WOMEN ASSOCIATION MATRICULATION HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL (78.92%)

2017

Concentrations: Business Math

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Data Analysis: Proficient in SQL, Python (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib), Excel
- Visualization: Skilled in Tableau, Power BI, and Matplotlib (Python)

CERTIFICATION:

- Data Analytics Masterclass NoviTech R&D
- Python for Data Science IBM
- Generative AI GUVI

LANGUAGE: Tamil (Native), English (Fluent)